Robert Garrett Collection of Ethiopic Manuscripts, 1600s-1900s: Finding Aid C0744.03
Manuscripts Division
- Series 1: Robert Garrett Collection of Ethiopic Manuscripts (C0744.03), 1570-1950; 82 boxes; 39 items
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 11: Homilies and Prayers to Jesus Christ, 1700-1730; 11; 1 box Parchment. 138 folios; 2 columns, 14 lines. Wooden boards coverd in red stamped leather. Fols. 1r-4v and 135v-138v are blank 17 x 24 cm
    Blank spaces left for the owner's name throughout.
    - Homilies on the Life of Jesus, 1700-1730; 1 box
      - Monday, early 18th century; 1 box Folio 5r-27r (Box 11)
      - Tuesday, early 18th century; 1 box Folio 27r-46r (Box 11)
      - Wednesday, early 18th century; 1 box Folio 46r-62r (Box 11)
      - Thursday, early 18th century; 1 box Folio 62v-83r (Box 11)
      - Friday, early 18th century; 1 box Folio 83v-102v (Box 11)
      - Saturday, early 18th century; 1 box Folio 102v-121v (Box 11)
      - Sunday, early 18th century; 1 box Folio 122r-135r (Box 11)
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 12: Antiphonal Chants (Mawāse't), 1800-1830; 12; 1 box Parchment. 34 folios; 3 columns, 31-32 lines. Wooden boards, leather spine. Folio 1r-v is blank 19 x 22 cm
    - The Antiphonary or Mawāse't, early 19th century; 1 box Folio 2r-134r (Box 12)
      Comprising antiphonal chants and psalms with cantillation signs for different festivals throughout the year.
    - Credo (Na'ammen), early 19th century; 1 box Folio 34r (Box 12)
      With cantillation signs.
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 13: Apostolic Epistles, 1750-1799; 13; 1 box Parchment. 26 folios; 2 columns, 20-22 lines. Wooden boards, stitched and open spine 17 x 21 cm
    Fols. 1r-2v and 26v are blank except for pen trials and some pencil sketches.
    - 1-2 Peter, second half of the 18th century; 1 box Folio 3r-11r (Box 13)
    - 1-2-3 John, second half of the 18th century; 1 box Folio 11r-19r (Box 13)
    - James, second half of the 18th century; 1 box Folio 19r-24v (Box 13)
    - Jude, second half of the 18th century; 1 box Folio 24v-26r (Box 13)
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 14: Organ of Praise of the Virgin Mary (Argānona Weddāsē), 1670-1730; 14; 1 box Parchment. 152 folios; 2 columns, 14 lines. Wooden boards, leather spine, skin case with strap. 16 x 16 cm
    - Hymn of Praise ('esagged) to the Virgin Mary, late 17th or early 18th century; 1 box Folio 1r-v (Box 14)
      Along with a curse directed at those who would steal, erase, burn, or take the book by force.
    - Three Miracles of the Virgin Mary, late 17th or early 18th century; 1 box Folio 2r-4v (Box 14)
    - Organ of Praise (Argānona Weddāsē), late 17th or early 18th century; 1 box Folio 5r-149r (Box 14)
      Marked for reading on each day of the week.
    - Calendrical Notes, late 17th or early 18th century; 1 box Folio 149r-150v (Box 14)
    - Salām or Hymn of Salutation to St. George, late 17th or early 18th century; 1 box Folio 150v-152v (Box 14)
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 15: Organ of Praise of the Virgin Mary (Argānona Weddāsē), 1630-1670; 15; 1 box Parchment.41 folios, 2 columns [fols. 31-141], 15-16 lines. Single wooden board (front), stitched and open spine. 18 x 20 cm
    Endnotes: [19th cent. hand] prayer against typhus, malaria, etc., fol. 1r.
    - A Prayer against Wild Animals, mid 17th century; 1 box Folio 1v-2r (Box 15)
    - Theological Exegesis on the Mystery of the Eucharist, mid 17th century; 1 box Folio 2v-4v (Box 15)
      17th-century hand.
    - A Prayer to the Virgin Mary, mid 17th century; 1 box Folio 5r-6v (Box 15)
      Different 17th cent. hand.
    - Part of a Hymn to the Virgin Mary, mid 17th century; 1 box Folio 6r (Box 15)
    - Argānona Weddāsē, mid 17th century; 1 box Folio 7r-141v (Box 15)
      Incomplete, divided into sections for Monday through Sunday. Leaves missing between fols. 131 and 132, also 134 and 135. Texts finishes in abrupto fol. 141v.
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 16: Antiphonary, 1770-1830; 16; 1 box Parchment. 57 folios; 3 columns, 31 lines. Wooden boards, only a fragment of the back board remaining, stitched and open spine 18 x 22 cm
    - Unidentified Liturgical Text, late 18th/early 19th century; 1 box Folio 1r-2r (Box 16)
    - Common Antiphonary (Me'erāf), late 18th/early 19th century; 1 box Folio 3r-57v (Box 16)
      Comprising a collection of antiphonal hymns and chants for the whole year with cantillation signs. Possibly incomplete (final leaf fol. 57v stained and illegible.).
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 17: The Miracles of Mary, 1800-1809; 17; 1 box Parchment. 75 folios; 2 columns, 20-21 lines. Wooden boards, leather spine. Fols. 1r-2v, 67v, 75v are blank 18.5 x 21.5 cm
    Former owners: Kenfa Māryām, also Kenfa Mikā'ēl and Zar'a Krestos.
    - Introduction to the Miracles (Mas'hafa Ser'at), 1800s; 1 box Folio 3r-8r (Box 17)
    - Prologue to the Miracles, 1800s; 1 box Folio 8r-9v (Box 17)
    - Miracles of Mary (Ta'ammera Māryām), 1800s; 1 box Folio 9v-66v (Box 17)
      62 miracles.
    - Miracle of Saint Marqoryos [sic], 1800s; 1 box Folio 66v-67r (Box 17)
    - Miracles of the Infant Jesus, 1800s; 1 box Folio 68r-75r (Box 17)
      10 miracles.
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 18: Praise of God, and Other Texts, 1650-1700; 18; 1 box Parchment. 147 folios; 2 columns, 17-20 lines. Wooden boards covered with tooled leather. 17 x 19 cm
    Folio numbering in pencil skips fol. 47 and repeats fol. 108.
    - Text Known as the Weddāsē Amlāk (Praise of God), 1650-1700; 1 box
      - Prayers and Supplications by Basil of Caesarea for Monday, 1650-1700; 1 box Folio 2r-20v (Box 18)
      - Prayers by Ephraim the Syrian for Tuesday, 1650-1700; 1 box Folio 20v-47r (Box 18)
        (wrongly marked as fol. 48)
      - Prayers Drawn from Homilies by Ephraim the Syrian for Wednesday, 1650-1700; 1 box Folio 48r-70r (Box 18)
      - Prayers by St. John Aragāwi Manfasāwi (John of Saba) for Thursday, 1650-1700; 1 box Folio 70r-97r (Box 18)
      - Prayers by Abba Sinoda the Abbot for Friday, 1650-1700; 1 box Folio 97r-108v (Box 18)
      - Prayers by Abba Pachomius for Friday, 1650-1700; 1 box Folio 108v-117v (Box 18)
      - Prayers by Athanasius of Alexandria for Saturday, 1650-1700; 1 box Folio 117v-132r (Box 18)
      - Prayers by Cyril of Alexandria for Sunday, 1650-1700; 1 box Folio 132r-145v (Box 18)
    - Lists of Arabic, Roman, Syrian, and Coptic Festivals, 1650-1700; 1 box Folio 146r-v (Box 18)
      Later hand..
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 19: Gospel of John, 1800-1850; 19; 1 box Parchment. 66 folios; 2 columns, 16-17 lines. Wooden boards with fragment of leather covering, leather spine, case with strap. 16 x 17.5 cm
    Various endnotes in different hands, including theological speculation and a list of the names of the months in "Greek" (in fact Coptic) and Hebrew, fols. 1v-3v.
    - Gospel of John, Marked for Readings on Each Day of the Week, 1800-1850; 1 box Folio 5r-66r (Box 19)
    - A Saying of Solomon, 1800-1850; 1 box Folio 66v (Box 19)
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 20: Horologium (Mas'hafa Sa'ātāt) Fragment, 1830-1870; 20; 1 box Parchment. 42 folios, 1 column, 16 lines. Parchment binding, leather slipcase with strap. 11 x 16 cm
    Endnotes recording various transactions, fols. 3r-4v and 22r-v.
    - Table Showing Monthly Calendar Measurements, mid 19th century; 1 box Folio 6r-v (Box 20)
    - Horologium (Mas'hafa Sa'ātāt) Fragment Comprising Petitions for the Night, mid 19th century; 1 box Folio 7r-22v (Box 20)
      (with occasional cantillation signs)
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 21: Horologium (Mas'hafa Sa'ātāt) Fragment, 1830-1870; 21; 1 box Parchment. 42 folios, 1 column, 16 lines. Wooden boards, hide case with strap. 10 x 14 cm
    Pen trials, fols. 1, 42r-v.
    - Horologium (Mas'hafa Sa'ātāt) Consisting of Various Liturgical Prayers, mid 19th century; 1 box Folio 2r-42r (Box 21)
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 22: Antiphonary (Mawāse't), 1830-1870; 22; 1 box Parchment. 35 folios; 2 columns, 14-15 lines. Wooden boards covered with stamped leather, hide case 10 x 15 cm
    Endnotes: various magical prayers, fols. 1r-2r; [in Amharic] note on the repetition of the 'Our Father' twelve times and the' Lord have mercy' forty-one times.
    Painting:
    Small miniature of the Archangel Michael (probably added later, circa early 20th century) holding a raised sword in his right hand, fol. 34v.
    Former owners: [later hand] Ramha Giyorgis, Walatta Dengel and Walatta Mikā'ēl.
    - Antiphonary (Mawāse't), mid 19th century; 1 box Folio 3r-33r (Box 22)
      With cantillation signs. Incomplete for the whole year
    - Calendar Table, mid 19th century; 1 box Folio 33v-34r (Box 22)
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 23: Psalter, 1800-1809; 23; 1 box Parchment. 75 folios, 1 column [fols. 1-172], 2 columns [fols. 173-175], 17 lines. Wooden board (front only), stitched and open spine, hide case. 12.5 x 13.5 cm
    - Book of Psalms, 1800s; 1 box Folio 1r-147v (Box 23)
    - Canticles of the Prophets, 1800s; 1 box Folio 148r-163r (Box 23)
    - Song of Songs, 1800s; 1 box Folio 163v-172v (Box 23)
    - Fragment of the Praise of Mary (Weddāsē Māryām), for Monday, 1800s; 1 box Folio 173r-175v (Box 23)
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 24: Psalter, 1730-1830; 24; 1 box Parchment. 136 folios, 1 column [fols. 1v-126r], 2 columns [fols. 126v-136v], 21 lines. Wooden boards, stitched and parchment spine, hide case. 15 x 18 cm
    Endnotes [bound upside down]: hymn to Mary, fols. 1r-2v.
    - Book of Psalms, mid 18th or early 19th century; 1 box Folio 3r-108v (Box 24)
    - Canticles of the Prophets, mid 18th or early 19th century; 1 box Folio 108v-120r (Box 24)
    - Song of Songs, mid 18th or early 19th century; 1 box Folio 120r-126r (Box 24)
    - Praise of Mary (Weddāsē Māryām), mid 18th or early 19th century; 1 box Folio 126v-136v (Box 24)
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 25: Apostolic Epistles, 1800-1850; 25; 1 box Parchment. 37 folios; 2 columns, 14-26 lines. No covers, stitched binding 15 x 17.5 cm
    Fol. 37v stained and partly illegible.
    - General Introduction to the Epistles and Introduction to 1 Peter, 1800-1850; 1 box Folio 1r-3r (Box 25)
    - 1 Peter, 1800-1850; 1 box Folio 3v-11v (Box 25)
    - 2 Peter With Introduction, 1800-1850; 1 box Folio 11v-17r (Box 25)
    - Introduction to 1-2 John, 1800-1850; 1 box Folio 17r-18v (Box 25)
    - 1-2 John, 1800-1850; 1 box Folio 18v-26v (Box 25)
    - 3 John With Introduction, 1800-1850; 1 box Folio 27r-28r (Box 25)
    - James With Introduction, 1800-1850; 1 box Folio 28r-36r (Box 25)
    - Introduction to Jude, 1800-1850; 1 box Folio 36r-27r (Box 25)
    - Jude, 1800-1850; 1 box Folio 37r-v (Box 25)
      Incomplete.
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 26: Calendar, 1600-1899; 26; 1 box Parchment. 16 folios, variously single block text, 2 columns and 3 columns, 20 lines. Stamped leather covers (no boards). 18 x 19.5 cm
    Also includes: list of rulers, some fictional, concluding with the kings of Ethiopia up to Zadengel (r. 1603-4) fols. 12v-13r; [19th century hand] continuation of the latter up to King Yohannes [IV] (r. 1871-89). [Different] Summary of various church regulations fols. 15r-16v.
    - Calendar With Columns for Phases of the Moon, Epacts, Fast Days and Days of Easter, Showing Dates of Certain Significant Ecclesiastical Events, early 17th century; 1 box Folio 1r-5v (Box 26)
      With commentary fols. 5v-7v.
    - Further Calendar Computations, early 17th century; 1 box Folio 8r-10v (Box 26)
      With commentary fols. 10v-12v.
    - Small Calendar Chart, early 17th century; 1 box Folio 14r (Box 26)
      With commentary fol. 14r-v.
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 27: Psalter, 1800-1809; 27; 1 box Parchment. 126 folios, 1 column [fols. 2r-114v], 2 columns [fols. 115r-125v], 25-29 lines. Wooden boards covered with stamped leather. 19 x 13.5 cm
    - Book of Psalms, 1800s; 1 box Folio 2r-98v (Box 27)
    - Canticles of the Prophets, 1800s; 1 box Folio 98v-109r (Box 27)
    - Song of Songs, 1800s; 1 box Folio 109r-114v (Box 27)
    - Praise of Mary (Weddāsē Māryām), 1800s; 1 box Folio 115r-125v (Box 27)
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 28: Organ of Praise of the Virgin Mary (Argānona Weddāsē), 1670-1699; 28; 1 box Parchment. 120 folios; 2 columns, 20-21 lines. Several leaves with a corner cut away towards the back of the manuscript. Wooden boards with leather spine. Fol. 120r is blank 15 x 18 cm
    - Argānona Weddāsē, late 17th century; 1 box Folio 1r-118v (Box 28)
      (divided into portions for the days of the week)
    - A Prayer of Supplication, late 17th century; 1 box Folio 119r-120 (Box 28)
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 29: Psalter, 1700-1799; 29; 1 box Parchment. 9 x 12 cm. 144 folios, long lines [fols. 1r-125r], 2 columns [126r-142], 23 lines, 1 column [fols. 143r-144v]. Wooden boards covered with stamped leather and wrapped in plain cloth, hide case. Mirror inserted inside back board. 9 x 12 cm
    Former owner: Walda Takla Haymānot.
    - Psalter, 1700-1799; 1 box
      - Psalms, 18th century; 1 box Folio 2r-106r (Box 29)
      - Canticles of the Prophets, 18th century; 1 box Folio 106r-117v (Box 29)
      - Song of Songs, 18th century; 1 box Folio 118r-125r (Box 29)
      - Ethiopic Syllabary, 18th century; 1 box Folio 125v (Box 29)
        (incomplete)
      - Praise of Mary (Weddāsē Māryām) in Sections for Each Day of the Week, 18th century; 1 box Folio 126r-136r (Box 29)
    - Other Texts, 1700-1799; 1 box
      - Arabic-Amharic Vocabulary and Phrase-Book, 18th century; 1 box Folio 1r-v and 142r (Box 29)
      - Calendar of Saints' Feast Days, 18th century; 1 box Folio 142v-143r (Box 29)
      - Short Magico-Medical Prescription, 18th century; 1 box Folio fol. 143r (Box 29)
      - Another Calendar of Festivals, 18th century; 1 box Folio 144r (Box 29)
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 30: Gospels of Mark and John, 1700-1799; 30; 1 box Parchment. 107 folios; 2 columns, 17 lines. Wooden boards, stitched and open spine 17 x 18 cm
    Former owner: Malke'a Krestos.
    - Gospel of Mary, 18th century; 1 box Folio 2r-45r (Box 30)
    - Salām or Hymn of Salutation, 18th century; 1 box Folio 45v-47v (Box 30)
      In part following a malke' format to the Archangel Gabriel.
    - Gospel of John, 18th century; 1 box Folio 48r-106r (Box 30)
    - Other Texts, 1700-1799; 1 box
      - A Religious Poem, 18th century; 1 box Folio 106r-107v (Box 30)
      - Partial List of Fast Days, 18th century; 1 box Folio 107v (Box 30)
      - Short Prayer, 18th century; 1 box Folio 107v (Box 30)
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 31: Theological Treatises, 1700-1730; 31; 1 box Parchment. 14 folios; 2 columns, 24-25 lines. No cover. 13 x 18 cm
    - Andemta Commentary in Amharic on the Nature of Christ, early 18th century; 1 box Folio 1v-2v and 13r-14v (Box 31)
      19th century hand.
    - Fragment of a Theological Treatise on the Nature of Jesus Refuting Qeb'at (Unction) Doctrine, early 18th century; 1 box Folio 3r-, 5r-10v (Box 31)
      18th century hand [?].
    - Fragment in Amharic of a Theological Treatise on the Nature of Christ, early 18th century; 1 box Folio 4r-v and 11r-v (Box 31)
      Different 19th century hand.
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 32: Anaphora of the Virgin Mary, late 18th century; 32; 1 item Parchment. 47 folios, 2 columns, 11 lines. Wooden boards, stitched and open spine. Folios 1r-2v are blank 12 x 18 cm (Box 32)
    Anaphora of the Virgin Mary (Qeddāsē Māryām) by Abba Heryāqos (Cyriacus) of Behensā, fols. 3r-47v.
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 33: The Gospel of Mary, 1800-1830; 33; 1 box Parchment. 62 folios; 1 column [fols 1-2], 2 columns [fols. 3-62], 15 lines. Wooden boards (back board partially missing) with stamped leather spine. 13 x 15.5 cm
    Pen trials, fol. 1r. [Different hand]
    - Prayer against Snake Bite, early 19th century; 1 box Folio 1v-2v (Box 33)
    - Gospel of Mark With Introduction, early 19th century; 1 box Folio 3r-62r (Box 33)
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 34: The Gospel of John, 1770-1799; 34; 1 box Parchment. 82 folios, 1 column, 17 lines. Wooden boards covered with leather and plain cloth, hide case 9.5 x 14 cm
    Pen trials, fols. 1, 2v and 82r.
    - Prayer against Hail and Prayer to the Tree of the Cross, late 18th century; 1 box Folio 2r (Box 34)
    - Gospel of John, Marked for Readings for Each Day of the Week, late 18th century; 1 box Folio 3r-82r (Box 34)
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 35: Anaphora of the Virgin Mary and Other Texts, 1700-1709; 35; 1 box Parchment. 39 folios, 1 column, 14-16 lines. Wooden boards. Folios 38v-39r are blank 10 x 17 cm
    Former owner: S'egē Mikā'ēl. Scribe: Misā'ēl.
    - Prayer against the Evil Eye, 1700s; 1 box Folio 1r-v (Box 35)
    - Anaphora of the Virgin Mary (Aqwatēta Qwerbān Za-Egze'tena Qeddest Dengel Māryām) by Abba Heryāqos (Cyriacus) of Behensā, 1700s; 1 box Folio 2r-29r (Box 35)
    - Repetitive Prayer to Jesus Christ Through the Intercession of the Virgin Mary, 1700s; 1 box Folio 29v-38r (Box 35)
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 36: The Gospel of John, 1770-1799; 36; 1 box Parchment. 93 folios, 2 columns, 16 lines. Wooden boards (split and repaired). 15 x 17 cm
    Endnotes: [19th century hand, red-brown ink] Prayers attributed to Moses for overcoming enemies, fols. 1r and 93v.
    - Introduction to the Story of the Ten Virgins, late 18th century; 1 box Folio 1v (Box 36)
    - Gospel of John, late 18th century; 1 box Folio 2r-93r (Box 36)
    - Calendar of Feast Days of the Apostles, late 18th century; 1 box Folio 93r-v (Box 36)
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 37: The Pillar of Light, 1600-1699; 37; 1 box Parchment. 17 folios; 2 columns, 20-24 lines. No covers 15 x 17 cm
    - Fragment of the Pillar of Light ('Amda Berhān), 18th century; 1 box Folio 1r-16v (Box 37)
      Beginning missing. A book of magical prayers and incantations and manual for the exorcism of demons.
    - Salām or Hymn of Salutation to Jesus, 18th century; 1 box Folio 17r-v (Box 37)
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 38: Liturgical Miscellany, 1700-1799; 38; 1 box Parchment. 40 folios, 1 column, 13-15 lines. Wooden boards. Fols. 40r-v are blank 11 x 6.5 cm
    - Malke'a Māryā, a Hymn to the Virgin Mary, 18th century; 1 box Folio 1r-17v (Box 38)
    - Malke'a 'Iyasu, a Hymn to Jesus Christ, 18th century; 1 box Folio 18r-32v (Box 38)
    - List of Annual Saints' Feast Days, 18th century; 1 box Folio 32v-34r (Box 38)
    - Hymn to the Virgin Mary, 18th century; 1 box Folio 34v-39 (Box 38)
      18th century hand.
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 39: Liturgical Miscellany, 1700-1799; 39; 1 box Parchment. 106 folios, 1 column, 12-13 lines. Wooden boards, stitched and open spine, hide case 9 x 13 cm
    Former owner: Kenfa Masqal.
    Scribe: (fols. 75r-85r) Kidāna Māryām.
    Fol. 106r-v is blank.
    - T'abiba T'abibān (lit. "Wisest of the Wise"), a Hymnological Composition in Praise of God, late 18th century; 1 box Folio 3r-53v (Box 39)
      With title page, fol. 2r.
    - A Hymn to Mary, late 18th century; 1 box Folio 53v-70r (Box 39)
    - A Miracle of Mary, late 18th century; 1 box Folio 70r-74r (Box 39)
    - Other Texts, 1700-1799; 1 box
      - A Prayer against the Evil Eye, late 18th century; 1 box Folio 74v (Box 39)
        Different later hand.
      - Petition to Jesus Through the Intercession of Mary, late 18th century; 1 box Folio 75r-85r (Box 39)
      - Prayer to Jesus, late 18th century; 1 box Folio 85v-86v (Box 39)
      - Petition to Jesus Through the Intercession of Mary, late 18th century; 1 box Folio 87r-105r (Box 39)
      - Prayer of Philomena (Filmonā), late 18th century; 1 box Folio 105r-v (Box 39)
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 40: Praise of God, and Other Texts, 1800-1899; 40; 1 box Parchment. 124 folios, 2 columns, 33 lines [fols. 3-10, 122-124], 18-19 lines [fols. 11-122]. Wooden boards with leather spine, hide case with strap. 13 x 14 cm
    Former owner: Kebra 'Ab.
    - Various Poems (qenē), 19th century; 1 box Folio 1r-2 (Box 40)
    - Text Known as the Weddāsē Amlāk (Praise of God), 1800-1899; 1 box
      - Prayers and Supplications by Basil of Caesarea for Monday, 19th century; 1 box Folio 11r-26v (Box 40)
      - Prayers by Ephraim the Syrian for Tuesday, 19th century; 1 box Folio 27r-47r (Box 40)
      - Prayers Drawn from Homilies by Ephraim the Syrian for Wednesday, 19th century; 1 box Folio 47v-62v (Box 40)
      - Prayers by St. John Aragāwi Manfasāwi (John of Saba) for Thursday, 19th century; 1 box Folio 63r-83r (Box 40)
      - Prayers by Abba Sinoda the Abbot for Friday, 19th century; 1 box Folio 83r-97v (Box 40)
      - Prayers by Athanasius of Alexandria for Saturday, 19th century; 1 box Folio 99r-109v (Box 40)
      - Prayers by Cyril of Alexandria for Sunday, 19th century; 1 box Folio 110r-122v (Box 40)
    - Various Prayers, 19th century; 1 box Folio 98r-v (Box 40)
    - Lamentations of the Soul (Seqoqāwa Nafs), 19th century; 1 box Folio 3r-10v and 122v-125v (Box 40)
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 41: Prophecies of Jesus and Prophecies of Sybil, 1800-1899; 41; 1 box Parchment. 18 folios, 1 column, 22-29 lines. Parchment cover. Fols. 17r-18v are blank 12 x 17 cm
    Illegible seal, fol. 16v,
    - Prophecies of Jesus (Fekkārē 'Iyasus), 19th century; 1 box Folio 1r-10r (Box 41)
    - Prophecies (lit. Wisdom) of Sybil (T'ebabā Labe'sit 'enta Semā Sābēllā), 19th century; 1 box Folio 10r-15r (Box 41)
    - Amharic Commentary on Arius, 19th century; 1 box Folio 15v-16v (Box 41)
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 42: The Book of Enoch, 19th century; 42; 1 item 81 folios, 2 columns, 22 lines. Fols. 81r-v are blank. Space for owner's name left blank, fol. 80v. Modern Library binding. Earlier European binding also in box. The old binding has the stamp of H. C. Reichardt, who can be identified as Henry Christian Reichardt (d. 1897), a missionary for the London Society for Promoting Christianity amongst the Jews. 18 x 13 cm (Box 42)
    Book of Enoch, with chapters indicated in red, fols. 1r-80v.
    The Ethiopic Book of Enoch (or 1 Enoch) is a complete Ge'ez translation of an ancient Jewish religious text, which claims to have been written by Enoch, the great-grandfather of Noah. The Ethiopian Orthodox Church regards the pseudepigraphic text as canonical. The present manuscript was one of those used in R. H. Charles, ed., The Book of Enoch, Translated from Professor Dillmann's Ethiopic Text... (Oxford: Clarendon Press, 1893).
    Custodial History
    Garrett Ethiopic MSS no. 42 may have previously been owned by Henry Christian Reichardt (d. 1817). Cf. Erho and Stuckenbruck 2013.
    Robert Garrett (1875-1961), Princeton Class of 1897, probably acquired the Enoch manuscript shortly after Reichardt's death.
    Bibliography
    Ted M. Erho and Loren Stuckenbruck, "A Manuscript History of Ethiopic Enoch." Journal for the Study of the Pseudoepigrapha 32:2 (2013), pp. 87-133, esp. 105-107.
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 43: Homilies and Miracles of the Archangel Gabriel, and Various Marian Texts, 1870-1930; 43; 1 box Parchment. 123 folios, 2 columns, 15 lines. 1 sheet of paper inserted at the front of the mss, and 8 paper folios sewn into the manuscript between fols. 85-86. Wooden boards covered with leather, leather spine and colored brocade over-sleeve. Fols. 1r-3v, 84v, 85r-87v, 122v-123v are blank 11.5 x 16 cm
    Former owner: Gabra Yohannes. Scribe: Gabra 'Iyasus.
    Loose slip of paper with a prayer between fols. 84 and 85.
    Paper inserts between fols. 85 and 86: homily for the festival of the Archangel Gabriel on Tāhsās 22, sheets 1r-4r. Miracles of St. George and Mary, sheets 4v-8v.
    Inserted between fols. 87 and 88: European printed colored image of the Virgin and the child Jesus.